<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on David Kambo</title>
    <link>https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on David Kambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 8: Water Catchment Area Management app</title>
      <link>https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/explore_ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/explore_ai/</guid>
      <description>In a team we created and deployed a water catchment area management web application. This web app is capable of not only showing the latest test site compliances but also historical ones as well. In addition, it shows time series data on various test parameters with future forecast on overall compliance based on the SANS 241-1 water quality standard. I was in charge of the Geospatial data page showing the waste water treatment plants (WWTP) and the various river water test sites on an interactive folium map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 7: Early Childhood Development</title>
      <link>https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/early_childhood_dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/early_childhood_dev/</guid>
      <description> Studyied data on children in the lower fee groups who were outliers in their category(positive deviants) based on school performance. Mined insights regarding factors, characteristics or combinations thereof associated with the positive deviants. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 6: Movie Recommender</title>
      <link>https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/movie_recomender/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/movie_recomender/</guid>
      <description> Created and deployed a recommender system for movies on a Streamlit app. Built both a content-based filtering model based on movie content consumed and collaborative-based filtering model based on user similarity. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 5: Climate Change Tweet Classification</title>
      <link>https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/climate_change_tweet_classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/climate_change_tweet_classification/</guid>
      <description> Deployed a Streamlit app that is able to classify whether or not a person believes in climate change based on their novel tweet data. Created a model that predicted tweet climate change sentiments with an accuracy of 90%. Utilized natural language processing to create features for the model. Presented our findings and app to an audience. Utilized Comet for version control. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: South African Language Identification</title>
      <link>https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/south_african_language_identification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/south_african_language_identification/</guid>
      <description> Created a model to identify which of South Africa&amp;rsquo;s 11 Official languages a given text is in. This was a two-day challenge with my model getting an f1_score of 0.95. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Spain Electricity Shortfall Challenge</title>
      <link>https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/spain_electricity_shortfall_challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/spain_electricity_shortfall_challenge/</guid>
      <description>In a team we created a model that would help estimate the three-hourly load shortfall in Spain precisely and deployed it on an Amazon Ec2 instance. This information would aid the government in determining how much the shortfall in their power is expected to be and in turn guide infrastructure spending so as to ensure that the right budget is allocated for renewable energy generation and the investment in power infrastructure is channeled in the right direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Database normalization</title>
      <link>https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/database_normalization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/database_normalization/</guid>
      <description> From an unnormalised database of two tables(products and transactions), I normalized its contents into the 3rd Normal Form(3NF) resulting into a database with nine tables. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Human Resource Case Study</title>
      <link>https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/human_resource_case_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kambodn.github.io/my_Portfolio/post/human_resource_case_study/</guid>
      <description> Created a Power BI dashboard used to gather insights and answer questions on employee absenteeism. Created new features using DAX. </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
